<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:isDelivered="{Boolean}false"
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-06T15:28:08.709Z"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
        cq:lastReplicated="{Date}2024-09-06T15:28:18.207Z"
        cq:lastReplicated_publish="{Date}2024-09-06T15:28:18.207Z"
        cq:lastReplicatedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
        cq:lastReplicatedBy_publish="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
        cq:lastReplicationAction="Activate"
        cq:lastReplicationAction_publish="Activate"
        cq:template="/conf/relife/settings/wcm/templates/page-content"
        jcr:isCheckedOut="{Boolean}true"
        jcr:mixinTypes="[cq:ReplicationStatus2,mix:versionable]"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="Terms &amp; Condition"
        jcr:uuid="c1bcf890-70d2-4624-85f2-e4b25ddf4fd9"
        sling:resourceType="relife/components/page">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="relife/components/container"
            layout="responsiveGrid">
            <container
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="relife/components/container"
                layout="responsiveGrid">
                <container
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="relife/components/container">
                    <section_7504393_copy
                        jcr:created="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:39.445+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:39.445+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/section">
                        <wrapper
                            jcr:created="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:56.411+02:00"
                            jcr:createdBy="admin"
                            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:56.411+02:00"
                            jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/wrapper">
                            <slideshow_copy_copy
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:23.638+02:00"
                                jcr:createdBy="admin"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-08-29T12:34:59.140Z"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="a.messori@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/slideshow"
                                accessibilityAutoItemTitles="false"
                                autopauseDisabled="false"
                                autoplay="false"
                                delay="5000">
                                <slide_video
                                    cq:panelTitle="Slide 1"
                                    jcr:created="{Date}2024-08-29T12:34:25.496Z"
                                    jcr:createdBy="a.messori@adiacent.com"
                                    jcr:description="&lt;p>Terms And Conditions&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-03T15:43:02.839Z"
                                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                    sling:resourceType="relife/components/slide-video"
                                    automaticDuration="true"
                                    descriptionFromPage="false"
                                    fileReference="/content/dam/relife/corporate/assets/menu/bg-relife-blue.jpg"
                                    imageFromPageImage="false"
                                    isDecorative="true"
                                    linkTarget="_self"
                                    textIsRich="true"/>
                            </slideshow_copy_copy>
                        </wrapper>
                    </section_7504393_copy>
                    <section_copy_copy_co
                        jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:37.739+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:37.739+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/section">
                        <wrapper
                            jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:45.393+02:00"
                            jcr:createdBy="admin"
                            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:45.393+02:00"
                            jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/wrapper">
                            <spacer
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-09-04T09:27:03.213Z"
                                jcr:createdBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-06T15:27:52.609Z"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/spacer"
                                spacer="25"/>
                            <title
                                cq:styleIds="[1723457725921,1723457132031]"
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-09-03T15:22:26.556Z"
                                jcr:createdBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-06T15:27:57.584Z"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/title"
                                linkTarget="_self"
                                type="h1"/>
                            <spacer_copy
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-09-04T09:27:03.213Z"
                                jcr:createdBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-04T09:27:08.002Z"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/spacer"
                                spacer="50"/>
                            <text
                                cq:styleIds="[1721211788361]"
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-09-03T15:23:00.955Z"
                                jcr:createdBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-09-03T15:44:09.318Z"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="d.mariotti@adiacent.com"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/text"
                                text="&lt;p>&lt;b>GENERAL CONDITIONS FOR THE USE AND CONSULTATION OF THE &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;>www.relife-aesthetics.com&lt;/a> WEBSITE&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The consultation and/or use of this website are subject to the general conditions laid out below (hereinafter the “General Conditions”). Consultation or use of this website implies the explicit acceptance of the General Conditions.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;br>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;b>1. INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Relife S.r.l. or other companies of the Menarini Group are the exclusive owners of, or are legitimately entitled to use, this website, including the contents, the graphic design, the texts, the graphic elements and the images present therein; the reproduction or any other use of such materials and elements not authorised in writing by the legitimate owner is expressly prohibited.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Relife S.r.l. or other companies of the Menarini Group are the exclusive owners of, or are legitimately entitled to use, all the trademarks (registered or de facto, denominative and/or figurative) and the other distinguishing marks displayed on this website and any use thereof without the prior, written consent of the owner is expressly prohibited.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Nothing that is contained in these General Conditions, or within the website, may be interpreted as the granting of a licence or other right to the industrial or intellectual property of the Menarini Group.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;b>2. LIABILITY&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The data contained in this website are supplied exclusively by experts in the medical sector (doctors and/or pharmacists) and communication experts and must be used exclusively for informative purposes.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Users of this website must consult their own doctors in relation to any questions, additional information or opinions on health matters (diagnoses, medical treatments etc.).&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Relife S.r.l. shall make all reasonably possible efforts to enter accurate and updated information on the website. Nevertheless, Relife S.r.l. cannot provide any statements or guarantees regarding the accuracy of the said information.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Neither Relife S.r.l. nor any other party engaged in the creation, production or publication of this website assumes any liability for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential or punitive damage deriving from the use of the website or from any errors or omissions in the contents of the same.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The links contained in the website offer access to other websites which are beyond the constant control of Relife S.r.l. Consequently, Relife S.r.l. cannot be held in any manner liable either for the contents of such websites (including, by way of example but not limited to, the links contained within them), or for the amendments and/or updates of the same.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The links are made available to visitors purely for reasons of convenience and practicality, and their inclusion within the website does not, in any case, imply any endorsement or sponsorship of the respective website by Relife S.r.l.. The use of third party websites is at visitor’s own risk and subject to the respective terms and conditions of such websites.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Internet is, by definition, at the service of the global community. Nevertheless, the pharmaceutical industry is governed by regulations aimed at restricting the information that can be supplied to the public, and the efficacy of such regulations is limited in territorial terms.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The aforementioned information is subject to amendment, and Relife S.r.l. declines all responsibility of any kind for any consequences deriving from changes, amendments or information provided within this website, and also for any damage or virus that may affect the electronic equipment or other property belonging to the user as a consequence of access to this website.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Relife S.r.l. reserves the right to update these General Conditions at any time.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;b>3. RESERVED CONTENTS FOR USERS&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Visits to this website may be registered solely for statistical purposes, in order to guarantee the continuity of the service and the constant improvement of the website itself.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Pursuant to the regulations in force, access to specific areas of the website, where applicable, could be reserved only for healthcare professionals (doctors and pharmacists) subject to registration of their data and assignation of an appropriate password.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>No identification/registration is required for visitors who merely access the unrestricted sections of the website.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;b>4. PRIVACY&lt;/b>&lt;br>&#xd;&#xa;The processing of the user’s personal data through the website is performed in compliance with Regulation 2016/679/EU and all other applicable legal provisions on personal data protection, including the aspects pertaining to the security and confidentiality of personal data, and in accordance with the Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy of the website, which is available on the website itself.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>If the User provides personal details (such as name, surname, e-mail address, professional titles, etc.) for the purposes of sending communications or notifications (including adverse event notifications), of signing up to restricted access areas of the website, or of taking part in any specific initiative (e.g., competitions) which may be present therein, these will be processed in the manner laid down in the information notice documents displayed in the relevant area of the website.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;b>5. CONTACTS&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>For information about the website, you may send a message using the form at &lt;a href=&quot;/ii/Contacts&quot;>http://www.relifecompany.com/Contacts&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                                textIsRich="true"/>
                        </wrapper>
                    </section_copy_copy_co>
                    <section_7504393
                        jcr:created="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:39.445+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:39.445+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/section">
                        <wrapper
                            jcr:created="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:56.411+02:00"
                            jcr:createdBy="admin"
                            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-07-29T14:35:56.411+02:00"
                            jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/wrapper">
                            <slideshow
                                jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:23.638+02:00"
                                jcr:createdBy="admin"
                                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:23.638+02:00"
                                jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="relife/components/slideshow"/>
                        </wrapper>
                    </section_7504393>
                    <section
                        jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:37.739+02:00"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:37.739+02:00"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/section">
                        <wrapper
                            jcr:created="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:45.393+02:00"
                            jcr:createdBy="admin"
                            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2024-06-28T16:52:45.393+02:00"
                            jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="relife/components/containers/wrapper"/>
                    </section>
                </container>
            </container>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
